PETE LEPAGE: 显示相对时间值
PETE LEPAGE: Displaying relative time values
现在已经是国际化 API
is now part of the Intl.
的一部分
API.
你可以指定垂直排版的文本的哪一侧
You can specify which side of the text underline
应该出现下划线
should appear on for text that flows vertically
和少许惊喜.
and fewer surprises.
我是 Pete LePage.
I'm Pete LePage.
让我们深入看看 Chrome 71 给开发者带来了什么新特性.
Let's dive in and see what's new for developers in Chrome 71.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
许多 web app 使用像 yesterday, in two days,
Many web apps use phrases like yesterday, in two days,
或者是 an hour age 此类的短语来表明什么事情发生了
or an hour ago to indicate when something happened
或者是即将发生, 而不是显示全部的日期
or is going to happen instead of displaying the full date
和时间.
and time.
显示相对时间变得如此普遍,
Displaying relative times has become so common
以至于大多数的 date/time 库提供了本地化功能
that most date/time libraries provide localized functions
来为我们处理这个.
to handle this for us.
实际上, 几乎我构建的每一个 web app,
In fact, with almost every web app I build,
moment.js 都是我添加的第一个库, 专门
moment.js is one of the first libraries I add expressly
为此.
for this purpose.
Chrome 71 引入了 Intl.relativeTimeFormat,
Chrome 71 introduces Intl.RelativeTimeFormat,
将这个工作转移给了 JavaScript 引擎
which shifts this work to the JavaScript engine
并且启用相对时间的本地格式化.
and enable localized formatting of relative times.
这会给与我们一个小的性能提升
This can give us a small performance boost
并且意味着我们只需要这些库作为 polyfill
and means we only need those libraries as a polyfill
当浏览器目前还没有支持这些新的 API.
when the browser doesn't support the new APIs yet.
使用它很简单.
Using it is simple.
创建一个新的实例同时指定地区, 然后只要
Create a new instance as specify the locale, then just
使用相对时间调用 format.
call format with the relative time.
查看 Matthias 的更新文章, 链接在下方.
Check out Matthias's updates post linked below.
当中文或者是日文文本被显示为垂直布局,
When Chinese or Japanese text is dispalyed in a vertical flow,
浏览器对于下划线应该显示在哪里是不一致的,
browsers are inconsistent with where the underline is placed.
有可能在左边或者是右边.
It may be on the left or on the right.
在 Chrome 71 中, text-underline-position 属性
In Chrome 71, the text underline position property
现在接受 left 或者是 right, 根据 CSS3 text decoration
now accepts left or right as part of the CSS3 text
规范的这部分.
decoration spec.
CSS3 text decoration 规范添加了一些新的属性
The CSS3 text decoration spec adds serveral new properties
其允许你指定像 使用的线的类型,
that allow you to specify things like what kind line
风格, 颜色, 位置 这样的东西.
to use, the style, the color, and position.
我们都感到很惊讶, 当我们访问某个网站, 其突然开始和我们说话.
We've all been surprised when we hit a site and suddenly it starts talking to us.
AutoPlay 策略阻止网站自动的
AutoPlay policies prevent sites from automatically
开始播放音频.
playing audio.
这些网站使用 speech synthesis API 替代.
These sites use the speech synthesis API instead.
从 Chrome  71 开始, speech synthesis API
Starting in Chrome 71, the speech synthesis API
现在需要一些用户在页面上的一些活动
now requires some kind of user activation on the page
来让其工作.
before it'll work.
这使得它和其他的 AutoPlay 策略对齐.
This brings it in line with other AutoPlay policies.
如果你在用户和页面交互之前
If you try and use it before the user has
尝试使用该 API, 这将会抛出一个错误.
interacted with the page, it will fire an error.
没有什么比 前往一个网站,
There's nothing worse than going to a site
其让你和你周围的同事感到意外
and having is surprise you and the coworkers
更糟糕的事情了.
sitting around you.
这些只是 Chrome 71 对于开发者的一些变化.
These are just a few of the changes in Chrome 71 for developers.
当然, 还有更多.
Of course, there's plenty more.
元素的 请求全屏方法
The element that requests fullscreen method
在 Android 上面已经可以自定义.
can now be customized on Android.
模块脚本请求的默认 凭证模式
The default credential mode for module scripe requests
已经从 omit 改为 same-origin.
has changed from omit to same origin.
并且为了使 Chrome 符合 Shadow DOM V1 规范,
And bringing Chrome in line with the Shadow DOM V1 spec,
Chrome 71 现在计算 :host(), :host-context(),
Chrome 71 now calculates the specificity
和 被插入的元素 的特殊性.
for :host(), :host-context(), and slotted elements.
如果你没有参加 Chrome Dev Summit, 或者是
If you didn't make is to Chrome Dev Summit, or
也许你参与了
maybe you did,
但是你没有看到所有的演讲,
but you didn't see all the talks,
查看 Chrome Dev Summit 2018 播放列表
check out the Chrome Dev Summit 2018 playlist
在我们的 YouTube 频道.
on our YouTube channel.
Ewa and Phil 研究使用 service worker
Ewa and Phil went into some neat techniques
的一些巧妙技巧.
for using service workers.
Mariko and Jake 谈论关于他们是如何搭建的 Squoosh.
Mariko and Jake talked about how they build Squoosh.
Katie and Houssein 讲述一些优秀的技术
Katie and Houssein covered some great techniques
来最大化你的站点的性能.
to maximize the performance of your site.
当然吗, 还有更多.
And of course, there are plenty more.
所以查看它们吧.
So check them out.
喔, 点击订阅按钮.
Oh, and click that subscription button.
每当我们发行一个新视频, 你就会收到一封邮件通知.
You'll get an email notification whenever we launch a new video.
我是 Pete LePage.
I'm Pete LePage.
一旦 Chrome 72 被发布,
And as sonn as Chrome 72 is released,
我将会在这里告诉你 Chrome 的新特性.
I'll be right here to tell you what's new in Chrome.